Valeriia Cherepanova

Interests_

My interests lie in developing accurate machine learning systems for practical applications, which are reliable, robust and fair. My research projects range from adversarial robustness and fairness of computer vision systems to tabular deep learning and meta-learning. I am also interested in explainability aspects of deep learning.

Education_

University of Maryland, College Park

College Park

PhD in Applied Mathematics

Aug 2018 - present

- · Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein
- Dean's Fellowship

University College London

London

MSc in Computational Biology (CoMPLEX)

Sept 2017 - Sept 2018

· Distinction

National Research University Higher School of Economics

Moscow

BSc in Mathematics Sept 2013 - June 2017

Industry Experience _

Amazon, Alexa Entertainment

Seattle

APPLIED SCIENTIST INTERN

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Developed ML solutions to classify different types of Alexa mistakes for improving Alexa Voice Search on FireTV.
- Built ML models for predicting popularity of FireTV Voice Searches from time-series data.

Amazon, Alexa Monitoring

Bellevue

APPLIED SCIENTIST INTERN

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

- Developed NLP solutions to improve transparency of 3P Alexa Skills through detecting incompliant privacy policy documents.
- Deployed the model in production and built an interactive dashboard.

Teradata Moscow

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

Jul 2016 - Oct 2016

• Designed a machine learning training course for engineers at the company.

Selected Publications _

LowKey: Leveraging Adversarial Attacks to Protect Social Media Users from Facial Recognition

V. Cherepanova, M. Goldblum, H. Foley, S. Duan, J. P. Dickerson, G. Taylor, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2021, [paper], [webtool]

Transfer Learning with Deep Tabular Models

R. Levin*, **V. Cherepanova***, A. Schwarzschild, A. Bansal, C. B. Bruss, T. Goldstein, A. G. Wilson, M. Goldblum *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2023, [paper], [GitHub]

Strong Data Augmentation Sanitizes Poisoning and Backdoor Attacks Without an Accuracy Tradeoff

E. Borgnia*, **V. Cherepanova***, L. Fowl*, A. Ghiasi*, J. Geiping*, M. Goldblum*, T. Goldstein*, A. Gupta* *The International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, & Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2021, [paper]*

Unraveling Meta-Learning: Understanding Feature Representations for Few-Shot Tasks

M. Goldblum, S. Reich*, L. Fowl*, R. Ni*, **V. Cherepanova***, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020, [paper]*

A Deep Dive into Dataset Imbalance and Bias in Face Identification

V. Cherepanova*, S. Reich*, S. Dooley, H. Souri, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein

TSRML Workshop at the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022, [paper]

Technical Challenges for Training Fair Neural Networks

V. Cherepanova*, V. Nanda*, M. Goldblum, J. P Dickerson, T. Goldstein *RAI Workshop at the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2021, [paper]

MetaBalance: High-Performance Neural Networks for Class-Imbalanced Data

A. Bansal, M. Goldblum, **V. Cherepanova**, A. Schwarzschild, C. B. Bruss, T. Goldstein *arXiv preprint*, [paper]

\sim	•		—	
$(\cap n)$	taran	CACA	nd Ta	IVC
COII	ICICII	ces a	nu ra	เกว

Transfer Learning with Deep Tabular Models

- Oral Presentation at the NeurIPS 2022 Table Representation Learning Workshop
- · Invited Talk at Arthur AI

A Deep Dive into Dataset Imbalance and Bias in Face Identification

- NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Trustworthy and Socially Responsible Machine Learning
- NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Algorithmic Fairness through the Lens of Causality and Privacy
- · NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Machine Learning Safety

Technical Challenges for Training Fair Neural Networks

• ICLR 2021 Workshop on Responsible AI

LowKey: Leveraging Adversarial Attacks to Protect Social Media Users from Facial Recognition

- ICLR 2021
- NeurIPS 2020 Resistance AI Workshop
- NeurIPS 2020 Workshop on Dataset Curation and Security

Reviewer Service
NeurIPS 2022, ICLR 2022, NeurIPS 2021, NeurIPS 2022 TSRML Workshop, ICLR 2021 RAI Workshop, IEEE TPAMI
Relevant Coursework

Machine Learning: Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Computational Linguistics, Algorithms in Machine Learning: Guarantees and Convergence, Foundations of Deep Learning

Signal Processing: Scientific Computing, Advanced Numerical Optimization, Mathematical Statistics, Probability Theory, Applied Stochastic Processes

Technical Skills		

Programming: Python (PyTorch, PySpark), basics of Matlab and R

^{*} indicates equal contribution